### **UX Researcher**

I'm a User Researcher with extensive experience in software development / project management and problem solving using technology and process. I am an advocate for the user while managing the needs of my organization to create products and services using user-centered design principles.

# **Key Competencies**

- Surveys
- Usability Testing
- Interviews
- Card sort
- Heuristic evaluations

- Task performance testing
- Cognitive walk-through
- Strategy and Planning
- Wireframes / Prototypes
- User flows

# Experience

### Masters of Human Computer Interaction + Design - UC Irvine, 8/2018 - 9/2019

Monterey Bay Aquarium (Capstone) - Design a digital notebook for use by the aquarium education program and participating schools.

- Competitive product research to understand features for existing products
- Literature reviews to identify themes around digital notebooks in and out of education
- Requirements analysis of existing research and documentation provided by client
- Ethnographic studies with students and aquarium staff in the field
- Performed user interviews and focus groups with staff
- Planned and executed usability testing
- Synthesized design recommendations

# Business Analyst (Contract) - Union Bank, 10/2017 - 7/2018

Contracted to lead the implementation of multiple mortgage document library using MS Sharepoint

- Conducted requirements-gathering interviews and needs analysis with cross functional teams
- Performed usability testing and analyzed results to support communication of findings and buy-in for updates
- Defined a change management plan to address communication of updated policies and changes to access
- Created long-term policies in collaboration with compliance, development, operations for updates and access to compliance and regulatory needs

# Senior Business Systems Analyst (Contract) - Alliance Healthcare Services, 11/2015 - 6/2017

- Contracted as user advocate within the development process to support enhancements and new software.
- Led the development and implementation of customer experience surveys using Qualtrics APIs.
- Performed user needs analysis, user interviews, wireframes and prototypes to support the development of an incident management portal and long-term reporting.
- performed usability testing and applied design principles and best practices for the rework of an account activity report used by sales.
- Performed usability testing, needs analysis and user interviews to support system usability issues for multiple externally facing products.
- Orchestrated collaborative planning and strategy sessions between project management, development, infrastructure.
- Created an IT engagement process to support utilization of resources and stages for quality.

### Sr. Business Analyst / Sr. Project Manager - Plaza Home Mortgage, 11/2012 - 10/2015

- Hired to identify and implement a Loan Origination System (LOS) to replace the sunset of a legacy LOS
- Performed user interviews, surveys and needs analysis to define user / system requirements
- Developed user flows applying lean methodologies and adherence to regulatory needs and system constraints
- Managed vendors through selection and implementation for ancillary services as part of LOS implementation
- Designed a quantitative model to support the selection of new software
- Mentored technical and business stakeholders

#### Business Analyst and Project Manager (Independent Consultant), 7/2011 - 10/2012

- Various consulting for healthcare, durable medical equipment supply and repair and financial services clients
- Managed the development of a website for equipment service requests using offshore resources - user requirements, user flows, usability testing on prototypes, acceptance testing, training and implementation to customer base
- Defined business requirements and updated user flows for application enhancements to support the implementation of acquired claims management software.
- Definition of business rules and user requirements for a payment services platform

Business Analyst / Project Manager (Contract) - Wells Fargo, 12/2010 - 6/2011

- Creation of an application to manage deposits and balances during account transition between Wachovia and Wells Fargo - user requirements, user flows and mockups, usability testing, compliance testing
- Managed a team of Fraud, Risk and Wealth Management personal to staff transition weekends.
- Created processes for issue resolution / escalation for wealth management customers
- Managed a cross-functional team to research and resolve classification of 500+ fraudulent accounts

# Strategic Alliances Manager (Contract / FTE) - Lender Processing Services, 2/2010 - 11/2010

- User needs and analysis with clients to support configuration of platform services
- Lead the creation of an appraisal management system involving cross-functional teams resulting in 1500+ business rules and integration with 10+ internal / external systems for a nationwide financial services client.

# **Previous Experience**

- Business Analyst and Project Management Consultant
- Business Process Manager / Director of Appraisal Administration New Century Mortgage
- Business Systems Analyst / Project Manager Option One Mortgage
- Web Development / Technology Liaison Anyloan.com / New Century Mortgage

#### Skills

HTML, CSS, usertesting.com, loop11, optimalsort, Hyland OnBase(ECM), SharePoint, Qualtrics.

#### **Education and Certifications**

- Masters of Human-Computer Interaction and Design UC Irvine
- Bachelors in Organizational Leadership Chapman University
- Six Sigma Black Belt Qualtec
- Certified Scrum Master (CSM)
- Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO)
- Project Management Professional (PMP)
- Software Product Management Certification University of Alberta